Matt Fitzpatrick

matt@50inthe314.com 314.680.1370 hire.50inthe314.com

Marketing professional, specializing in brand management and promotions through digital channels including digital publishing, search, social, and email. Expertise in project management, content creation, digital development, and analysis of metrics for continuous improvement. Creates unique opportunities for brands to cultivate a voice while adhering to brand guidelines, budgets, and schedules. Adapts easily to changing targets, trends, and tech.

Experience

Senior Engineer-Digital Marketing, Mastercard, St. Louis, MO, September 2017 - Present

- Project Manager and Digital Strategist for launch and promotional development of Mastercard online properties worldwide, including Mastercard.com, Masterpass, Priceless, and donation / charitable platforms.
- Implemented a total rebranding of Mastercard.com across 88 countries. Moved sites to a unified CMS platform to streamline projects among international teams and ensure quality across all facets of our online presence.
- Managed our agile environment across teams worldwide by leading scrum meetings, planning sessions and brainstorms. Acted as gatekeeper to ensure proper use of our online platforms, and launches with minimal downtime.
- Worked across multiple time zones and languages to ensure properties and programs are launched properly, and optimised for performance. Analyzed growth and reach of programs from conception to decommission.

Digital Marketing Specialist, Saint Louis University, St. Louis, MO, January 2014 - August 2017

- Led digital marketing efforts (web, email, CRM, social media campaigns), as well as collaboration on traditional tactics.
- Developed and launched multi-channel campaigns for multiple programs, reaching diverse target markets including millennial students, young professionals, and B2B. Continuously optimized campaigns using research and analytics.
- Discovered new channels and tactics to reach our audience. Created and presented action plans to increase
 market presence, and report back to management with key progress indicators and strategies for continuous
 improvement.
- Implemented content marketing strategies and calendars. Organically increased audience 40%, reach 85%.
- Increased site traffic by 20% year to date, with peak increases in social, email, and organic search traffic.
- Maintain paid ad placements online, including search, banner ads, and retargeting. Develop strategies for long term branding initiatives and short term events. Optimized CPM and CPC while maintaining our target market.
- Managed staff, vendors, and budgets. Work with both internal teams and outside agencies to expand marketing efforts.

Marketing / Account Manager, The Able Few, St. Louis, MO, November 2012 - November 2013

- Managed marketing for digital development firm, including B2B, social media, press releases, and events.
- Worked in a continuous release cycle, where many hands were on a single project and concerted contact with the client was required to maintain the expected level of accuracy and excellence in our products.
- Developed business plans, site maps, and feature release timelines for web applications that have been featured at South By Southwest, Mashable.com, and other tech events and publications.

Account Manager, CTM Media Group, St. Louis, MO, October 2011 - November 2012

- Managed over 400 traditional and digital advertising placements for area attractions and tourist hotspots.
- Introduced a new digital marketing medium to the St. Louis area. Facilitated placement in high end hotels and premium attractions. Increased digital reach in the St. Louis area to 2.5 million visitors annually.
- Created and presented analytical reports and research studies for our clients, showing where their marketing plan succeeded and giving insight on how to improve when needed.

50 in the **314** (Freelance Consultancy), St. Louis, MO, January 2010 - Present

- Acts as consultant, designer / developer, and digital strategist for area advertising agencies (Scorch Agency, Osborn & Barr, Infuz, Caviar Creative), startups, small businesses, political campaigns and local charities.
- Went one-on-one to discover client needs, develop strategies, and execute digital and traditional marketing campaigns.
- Managed multiple brands digital presence, including social, event, promotional tactics, and digital media buys.

Proficiencies

- Digital Marketing Adept in many digital marketing suites, including Adobe Marketing Cloud and Salesforce.
- Media Buying AdSense, AdWords, social platforms including Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter, Instagram.
- Media Production Expertise in Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, and Final Cut Pro.
- Development Full Wordpress Builds, Read and Write CSS, PHP & Ruby, Operates well in most CMS's.

Education

Saint Louis University - St. Louis, MO MBA - Marketing Focus, Graduated May 2017

Webster University - St. Louis, MO BA - Advertising and Marketing Communications, Graduated with honors, May 2010